Guide to the James Marshall Osborn Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Box and Folder List, 1960
  - Hayward, John Davy, 1905-1965, 1954-65 (Box 36, Folder 724-725)
    Bibliographer, editor, collector, etc.
  - Hay, Millicent V., 1974 (Box 36, Folder 726)
    Robert Sidney
  - Hazen, Allen Tracy, 1904-1977, 1938-76 (Box 36, Folder 727-728)
  - Healey, George N., 1944-64 (Box 37, Folder 729)
  - Hecht, J. Jean, 1965-66 (Box 37, Folder 730)
  - Heffer, W. & Sons Ltd., 1938-54 (Box 37, Folder 731)
  - Heinz, Henry John, III, 1962-63 (Box 37, Folder 732)
  - Heise, John, Autographs, 1950-53 (Box 37, Folder 733)
  - Helyar, L. E. James, 1971-72 (Box 37, Folder 734)
    University of Kansas Libraries
  - Hemlow, Joyce, 1953-76 (Box 37, Folder 735-745)
    McGill, Burney Family
  - Hendel, Charles William and Elizabeth, 1963-69 (Box 37, Folder 746)
    New Haven friends
  - Henning, Basil Duke and Alison, 1956-74 (Box 37, Folder 747)
    Yale, Parliamentary history
  - Hepplewhite, Francis, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 748)
  - Hexter, Jack H., 1966-74 (Box 37, Folder 749)
    Yale, Parliamentary Diaries
  - Hill, Peter Murray, Ltd., 1949-66 (Box 38, Folder 750)
  - Hill, Winifred L., 1955-62 (Box 38, Folder 751)
  - Hille, Einar, 1956 (Box 38, Folder 752)
  - Hilles, Frederick Whiley, 1900-1975, 1938-75 (Box 38, Folder 753)
    Yale English Department, 18th century scholar and collector
  - Hinman, Charlton Joseph Kadio, 1948-67 (Box 38, Folder 754)
  - Hiscock, W. G., 1955-65 (Box 38, Folder 755)
    Librarian, Christ Church, Oxford, Whythorne
  - The Hispanic Society of America, 1953-61 (Box 38, Folder 756)
  - The Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 757)
  - Hoag, Paul F., 1951 (Box 38, Folder 758)
  - Hobson, Anthony R. A., 1956-69 (Box 38, Folder 759)
    Sotheby's
  - Hodgart, Matthew, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 760)
    Verifying a 17th century cookery book
  - Hodges Figgis & Co. Ltd., 1953-67 (Box 38, Folder 761)
  - Hodges, John C., 1939-64 (Box 38, Folder 762)
    University of Tennessee, Congreve
  - Hodnett, Edward, 1938-46 (Box 38, Folder 763)
    Columbia, English Inst.
  - Hofer, Philip, 1940 (Box 38, Folder 764)
    Harvard University Library
  - Hofmann & Freeman, Ltd., 1965-73 (Box 38, Folder 765)
  - Hogan, Charles Beecher, 1952-72 (Box 38, Folder 766)
    Yale, scholar, collector
  - Holden, Reuben Andrus, 1951-71 (Box 38, Folder 767)
    Yale, Secretary of the University
  - Holland Brothers, 1949-64 (Box 38, Folder 768)
  - Hollings, Frank, 1939-63 (Box 38, Folder 769)
  - Holloway, Owen E., 1937 (Box 38, Folder 770)
  - Hooker, Edward Niles, d. 1957, 1939-62 (Box 38, Folder 771-773)
    UCLA, Dryden
  - Hopkins, Robert H., 1970 (Box 39, Folder 774)
  - Horgan, Paul, 1964-76 (Box 39, Folder 775)
    Wesleyan, novelist, Athenaeum, etc.
  - Horn, Albert J., 1955-56 (Box 39, Folder 776)
    Old friend of J. M. Osborn's father
  - Horst, Paul and Dorothy, 1939-75 (Box 39, Folder 777-778)
  - Horrath, Adam D., 1972-73 (Box 39, Folder 779)
    The Club, The Press of Case Western Reserve University
  - Hotchkiss, Gerald G., 1961 (Box 39, Folder 780)
  - Hostson, Leslie, 1956-63 (Box 39, Folder 781)
  - Houghton, Arthur A., Jr., 1951-58 (Box 39, Folder 782)
    Morgan Library, Johnsonian
  - Houghton, Walter E., 1939-41 (Box 39, Folder 783)
  - House, Madeline, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 784)
    Letters of Dickens edn.
  - Houston, Andre, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 785)
  - Howard, Sir Algar, 1947-49 (Box 39, Folder 786)
  - Howard, Lady Katherine, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 787)
  - Howard-Hill, Trevor H., 1964 (Box 39, Folder 788)
    University of Birmingham
  - Howe, Ellic, 1971 Jan 3 (Box 39, Folder 789)
    Sidney horoscope (astrologer)
  - Howell, Alfred C., 1941 (Box 39, Folder 790)
    Grolier Club
  - Howell, Roger, Jr., 1968-72 (Box 39, Folder 791)
    Bowdoin, Sidney
  - Howes Bookshop, Ltd., 1938-60 (Box 39, Folder 792)
  - Hubler, Edward L., 1949-63 (Box 39, Folder 793)
    Princeton
  - Hudson, Derek, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 794)
    Fox
  - Hudson, Wilson M., 1951 (Box 39, Folder 795)
  - Hufstader, Dom Anselm, 1964-68 (Box 39, Folder 796)
    Portsmouth Priory
  - Hughes, Peter, 1961-68 (Box 39, Folder 797)
  - Hugo, Harold, 1954-69 (Box 39, Folder 798)
    Meriden Gravure
  - Hume, Robert, 1969-74 (Box 39, Folder 799)
  - Hunt, Richard, 1954-72 (Box 39, Folder 800)
    Keeper of Western MSS, Bodleian
  - Hunter, C. Stuart, 1964-68 (Box 39, Folder 801)
  - Hunting, Robert S., 1949-58 (Box 39, Folder 802)
    Atterbury
  - Huntington Library and Art Gallery, Henry E., 1939-64 (Box 39, Folder 803)
  - Hurlimann, Martin, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 804)
  - Hurst, James E., 1952-55 (Box 39, Folder 805)
    Lichfield Johnson Society
  - Hutton, B. G., 1961-62 (Box 39, Folder 806)
    Public Record Office of Northern Ireland, Macartney
  - Hyde, Donald Frizell, 1909-1966, 1953-65 (Box 39, Folder 807)
  - Hyde, Mary Morley (Crapo), 1951-76 (Box 39, Folder 808-809)
    Johnson and Thrale collector, scholar, etc.
  - Hyman, Leonard, Ltd., 1949-64 (Box 39, Folder 810)
  - Hysham, Julia, 1939-40 (Box 39, Folder 811)
    Warton
  - Illinois, University of, Library, 1951-56 (Box 40, Folder 812)
  - The Index Society, 1947-64 (Box 40, Folder 813-816)
  - Inglis, Helen, 1953-73 (Box 40, Folder 817)
    Ohio cousin
  - Ingoldsby, William, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 818)
  - International Autographs, 1960-67 (Box 40, Folder 819)
  - International Institute of Arts and Letters, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 820)
  - Irving, Robert Grant, 1962-64 (Box 40, Folder 821)
    Young Yale-Oxford friend
  - Isaacs, Alexander J., 1950 (Box 40, Folder 822)
  - Isaacs, Enid, 1971-76 (Box 40, Folder 823)
  - Isaacs, Jack, 1951-68 (Box 40, Folder 824)
  - Isham, Sir Gyles, Bart., 1957-73 (Box 40, Folder 825)
    Stanley and Dryden
  - Isham, Ralph, 1946-50 (Box 40, Folder 826)
  - Itineraries (JMO and MLO), 1954-68 (Box 40, Folder 827)
  - Ivanovic, Vane, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 828)
    Rabbards MS
  - Jack, Ian, 1954-71 (Box 41, Folder 829)
    Brasenose
  - Jackson, Noelle, 1974-76 (Box 41, Folder 830)
  - Jackson, William Alexander, 1905-1964, 1938-63 (Box 41, Folder 831)
  - James, Evan, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 832)
    Steward of Christ Church, Oxford
  - Jameson, Harriet C., 1965 (Box 41, Folder 833)
  - Jameson, R. D., 1940-42 (Box 41, Folder 834)
    Library of Congress
  - Jantzen, H. T., 1959-68 (Box 41, Folder 835)
  - Jasinski, Beatrice W., 1964-65 (Box 41, Folder 836)
    Mme. de Stael
  - Jeans, Susi, Lady, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 837)
    Braye Lute book
  - Jephson, Maurice Denham, 1967 (Box 41, Folder 838)
    Jephson, Malone
  - Jobling, Valerie, 1965-74 (Box 41, Folder 839)
    History of the University of Oxford
  - Johnson, Foster Macy, 1968-76 (Box 41, Folder 840)
    Printing
  - Johnson, Frank M., 1939-67 (Box 41, Folder 841)
  - Johnson, Helen Armstead, 1967 (Box 41, Folder 842)
  - Johnson, James William, 1974-75 (Box 41, Folder 843)
  - Johnson, John, 1936-40 (Box 41, Folder 844)
    Printer to the University, Oxford
  - Johnson, Maurice, 1951 Oct 17 (Box 41, Folder 845)
    J. M. Osborn's critique of paper for PMLA
  - Johnson, Philip A., 1956 (Box 41, Folder 846)
    City government
  - Johnson, Robert C., 1966 (Box 41, Folder 847)
    Yale Parliamentary Diaries
  - Johnson, S. F., 1958-59 (Box 41, Folder 848)
  - The Johnson Society of London, 1953-67 (Box 41, Folder 849)
  - The Johnsonians, 1951-58 (Box 41, Folder 850)
  - Johnstone, Harry Diack, 1965-66 (Box 41, Folder 851)
    Maurice Greene
  - Jones, Claude E., 1938-56 (Box 41, Folder 852)
    UCLA, Isaac Reed
  - Jones, Howard Mumford, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 853)
    Harvard Library Bulletin
  - Jones, Louis C., 1950 (Box 41, Folder 854)
    New York State Historical Society
  - Jones, Richard Foster, 1937-62 (Box 41, Folder 855)
    Washington University, St. Louis
  - Jones, Thomas, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 856)
  - Jones, W. Powell, 1941 (Box 41, Folder 857)
    Western Reserve University, MLA
  - Jordan, Richard D., 1969-75 (Box 41, Folder 858)
  - Judd, Howard Carter, 1954-73 (Box 41, Folder 859)
    Morgan Guaranty friend
  - Juel-Jensen, Bent, 1960-70 (Box 41, Folder 860)
    Oxford physician
  - Kahrl, George M., 1928-76 (Box 42, Folder 861-862)
    Edwina College, Garrick correspondence
  - Kaufman, Paul, 1963-64 (Box 42, Folder 863)
    Botesdale MSS
  - Kearl, Stanley Brandon, 1952-53 (Box 42, Folder 864)
    Sculptor
  - Keast, William Rea, 1941-74 (Box 42, Folder 865)
    18th century, Cornell, Wayne State, Texas
  - Keller, Deane and Katherine, 1952-70 (Box 42, Folder 866)
    Portrait painter, New Haven friends
  - Kelley, Maurice, 1945-64 (Box 42, Folder 867)
  - Kelley, Philip, 1963-69 (Box 42, Folder 868)
    Browning, Landor
  - Kelley, Robert E., 1968 (Box 42, Folder 869)
  - Kemp, A. R. D., 1957 (Box 42, Folder 870)
    Whythorne, Rabbards
  - Kendrick, Harold, 1960-73 (Box 42, Folder 871)
    New Haven Symphony Orchestra manager
  - Kendrick, Sir Thomas, 1961-68 (Box 42, Folder 872)
  - Kenyon College, 1963 (Box 42, Folder 873)
    Honorary degree and commencement address, 1963
  - Ker, Neil, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 874)
  - Kerby-Miller, Charles, 1961-62 (Box 42, Folder 875)
    The Scriblerian
  - Kermode, Frank, 1919-, 1953-69 (Box 42, Folder 876)
    Critic, etc.
  - Kerr, Chester, 1957-75 (Box 42, Folder 877)
    Director, Yale University Press
  - Kerr, David R., 1940-46 (Box 42, Folder 878)
    Research assistant, 1939-41
  - Kerr, Lord John (Sanders of Oxford Ltd.), 1960-62 (Box 42, Folder 879)
  - Kerr, Willis, 1941-42 (Box 42, Folder 880)
    Claremont College librarian, Dryden
  - Kerslake, Sir John, 1967-73 (Box 42, Folder 881)
    NPG
  - Kertesz, Stephen, 1949-53 (Box 42, Folder 882)
    Hungarian diplomatic history
  - Ketton-Cremer, Robert Wyndham, 1906-1969, 1938-69 (Box 42, Folder 883)
    Felbrigg Hall, Walpole
  - Kidd, Constance, 1966-67 (Box 43, Folder 884)
    Urquhart
  - Kilby, Clyde S., 1941 (Box 43, Folder 885)
    Index to Defoe's Review
  - Kilgour, Frederick G., 1960-69 (Box 43, Folder 886)
    Yale Medical Librarian
  - Killanin, Michael Morris, 3rd Baron, 1914-, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 887)
    Kneller
  - Kimbrough, Robert, 1969-70 (Box 43, Folder 888)
    Sidney paper at MLA
  - King, James, 1971-72 (Box 43, Folder 889)
  - King, Raphael, Ltd., 1950-54 (Box 43, Folder 890)
  - Kingston Galleries (Kenneth W. Rendell), 1962-68 (Box 43, Folder 891)
  - Kinney, Arthur F., 1970-75 (Box 43, Folder 892)
    Editor, English Literary Renaissance
  - Kinsley, James, 1961-68 (Box 43, Folder 893)
    Nottingham, Dryden
  - Kirk, Rudolf, 1939-62 (Box 43, Folder 894)
    Rutgers, English Inst., etc.
  - Kiwanis Club, 1953-70 (Box 43, Folder 895)
  - Klein, Holger M., 1972-76 (Box 43, Folder 896)
    University of East Anglia, Spence
  - Klejman Gallery, J. J., 1955-60 (Box 43, Folder 897)
    African art in Linton Collection
  - Klibansky, Raymond, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 898)
  - Klima, Slava, 1952-76 (Box 43, Folder 899-904)
    J. M. Osborn's research assistant, 1952-55, Spence and Burney, McGill University
  - Knapp, Mary Etta, 1950-76 (Box 44, Folder 905)
  - Knapp, Wilfred, 1968-75 (Box 44, Folder 906)
    St. Catherine's College, Oxford
  - Knight, Douglas Maitland, 1953-64 (Box 44, Folder 907)
    Lawrence College, Wisconsin
  - Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1892-197?, 1938-73 (Box 44, Folder 908)
    Yale University librarian, bibliophile
  - Knowles, Edwin B., 1903-1967, 1934-67 (Box 44, Folder 909-910)
    NYU, Pratt Institute
  - Kokeritz, Helge, 1957-58 (Box 44, Folder 911)
    Yale English Department
  - Kolb, Gwin Jackson, 1919-, 1954-66 (Box 44, Folder 912)
    University of Chicago, Johnsonian
  - Kristeller, Paul Oskar, 1953-70 (Box 44, Folder 913)
    Columbia, Renaissance MSS
  - Kruse, Cornelius, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 914)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1893-, 1952-59 (Box 44, Folder 915)
    Columbia, Wing review
  - Kuhn, Joaquin, 1969-74 (Box 44, Folder 916)
  - Kuin, Caroline (Davidson), 1973-76 (Box 44, Folder 917)
    Ex-wife of J. M. Osborn's research assistant
  - Kuin, Roger, 1967-74 (Box 44, Folder 918)
    J. M. Osborn's research assistant, 1967-69, Sidney
  - Kuist, James M., 1966-67 (Box 44, Folder 919)
  - Kupersmith, William, 1973-75 (Box 44, Folder 920)
    University of Iowa, Philological Quarterly
  - Kybal, Vlastimil, 1944-49 (Box 44, Folder 921)
    His nephew's immigration to United States
  - Lada-Mocarski, Laura (Polly), 1965-76 (Box 45, Folder 922)
    Bookbinder and friend
  - Laflin, Louis E., Jr., 1958 Dec 2 (Box 45, Folder 923)
    Benedick's song from Much Ado
  - Lam, George, 1941-68 (Box 45, Folder 924)
    Walpole Edition, Dodsly's Collection, NHSO
  - Lamar, Howard, 1961-69 (Box 45, Folder 925)
  - Landa, Louis, 1944-72 (Box 45, Folder 926)
    Princeton, 18th century
  - Landor, John W. L., 1963 (Box 45, Folder 927)
    Landor letters
  - Lane, F. Thatcher, 1948 (Box 45, Folder 928)
    Bet on Truman's reelection
  - Lang, Cecil, 1952-74 (Box 45, Folder 929)
    Syracuse, University of Virginia, Tennyson
  - Langford, Paul, 1973-76 (Box 45, Folder 930)
    Lincoln College, Oxford, 18th century politics
  - Larabee, Stephen, 1937-40 (Box 45, Folder 931)
    Princeton, Neo-Hellenism
  - Lascelles, Mary, 1959-70 (Box 45, Folder 932)
    Somerville College, Oxford, Johnson
  - Laslett, Peter, 1954-69 (Box 45, Folder 933)
    Trinity College, Cambridge
  - Last, G. H., 1938-50 (Box 45, Folder 934)
  - Lawrence, Harold, 1970-73 (Box 45, Folder 935)
    London Symphony Orchestra, Das Klagende Lied
  - Lawson & Co., E. M., 1938-66 (Box 45, Folder 936)
  - Lea, Richard J., 1934-51 (Box 45, Folder 937)
  - League of Women Voters of Connecticut, Inc., 1954-56 (Box 45, Folder 938)
  - Lebans, Elizabeth, 1965 (Box 45, Folder 939)
    William Seward
  - Leddy, Frank, 1967-72 (Box 45, Folder 940)
    President, University of Windsor, Ontario, Rome
  - Lederman, Milton B., 1950 (Box 45, Folder 941)
  - Lee, Isabel, 1939-42 (Box 45, Folder 942)
    Research assistant, periodical index
  - Lee, Kate, 1952 (Box 45, Folder 943)
  - Lee, Richard C., 1951-69 (Box 45, Folder 944)
    Mayor of New Haven
  - Leeds, Duke of, 1963-64 (Box 45, Folder 945)
    Family papers
  - Leeney, Robert, 1965-67 (Box 45, Folder 946)
    New Haven Register
  - LeFanu, William, 1970-75 (Box 45, Folder 947)
    English music (contemporary)
  - Legge, Christopher, 1956-66 (Box 45, Folder 948)
    Librarian, American University in Beruit, Bradford Jr. College
  - Leggett, Glenn H., 1952 (Box 45, Folder 949)
    Johnson's Life of Pomfret
  - Legouis, Pierre, 1939-67 (Box 45, Folder 950)
  - Lehman, Robert Owen, 1963-65 (Box 45, Folder 951)
    Facsimiles of music MSS
  - Lehmann-Haupt, Hellmut, 1940 (Box 45, Folder 952)
    Columbia, book binding
  - Leiber, Fritz, 1948 Nov 22 (Box 45, Folder 953)
  - Leigh, R. A., 1965-73 (Box 45, Folder 954)
    Rousseau and Burney, Trinity College, Cambridge
  - Lemon, Luella Dryden, 1947 (Box 45, Folder 955)
  - Levin, Harry, 1933-55 (Box 45, Folder 956)
    Neo-Hellenism
  - Levy, Charles S., 1967-72 (Box 45, Folder 957)
    Cornell, Sidney
  - Lewis, Clive Staples, 1898-1963, 1935-36 (Box 45, Folder 958)
  - Lewis, Douglas, 1962-63 (Box 45, Folder 959)
  - Lewis, Wilmarth Sheldon, 1895-1979, 1935-76 (Box 46, Folder 960-965)
    Walpole, collecting, libraries, Yale
  - Library of Congress, 1940-59 (Box 46, Folder 966)
  - Lieb, Clerence William and family, 1935-69 (Box 46, Folder 967-968)
    Montgomery cousins
  - Liebert, Herman Wardwell, 1911-, 1947-73 (Box 46, Folder 969)
    Johnson, Yale University Library
  - Linton, Calvin D., 1972-73 (Box 46, Folder 970)
    George Washington University, MHRA
  - Linton Collection, 1952-62 (Box 46, Folder 971)
    African art, given by J. M. Osborn to Yale Art Gallery
  - Lipking, Lawrence, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 972)
  - Lipetz, Ben-Ami, 1972 Dec 12 (Box 46, Folder 973)
    Comments on Ruminations on Method in Literary Research
  - Lister, Unity, Dame, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 974)
  - Little, Katherine (Day), 1961 (Box 46, Folder 975)
    Chevalier Ramsey
  - Lockwood, Willard A., 1960-74 (Box 47, Folder 976)
    Wesleyan University Press
  - Loftis, John, 1949-72 (Box 47, Folder 977)
  - London County Council, 1960-62 (Box 47, Folder 978)
    Historic plaque on Malone's house
  - Long, Percy W., 1939-47 (Box 47, Folder 979)
  - Lonsdale, Roger, 1958-76 (Box 47, Folder 980-984)
    J. M. Osborn's research assistant, 1958-60, Balliol, Dr. Burney
  - Loos, Melvin, 1897-1971, 1944-73 (Box 47, Folder 985)
    Columbia University Press
  - Lord, George de Forest and Ruth (du Pont), 1953-76 (Box 47, Folder 986)
    Yale English department, POAS
  - Lothian, John M., 1958-63 (Box 47, Folder 987)
    Aberdeen
  - Loveday, T., 1955-59 (Box 47, Folder 988)
  - Low, David, Booksellers Ltd., 1951-52 (Box 47, Folder 989)
  - Low, Isabel R., 1935-70 (Box 47, Folder 990)
    Old Illinois friend
  - Lowe Bros. Ltd., 1951-64 (Box 47, Folder 991)
  - Lowe, G. Burman, 1954 (Box 47, Folder 992)
  - Lowny, Howard, 1941-42 (Box 47, Folder 993)
  - Lumsden, David, 1953 (Box 47, Folder 994)
  - Lund, F. Edward, 1963-64 (Box 47, Folder 995)
    President, Kenyon College
  - Lupton, Lewis F., 1972 (Box 47, Folder 996)
  - Lydenberg, H. M., 1939-40 (Box 47, Folder 997)
    Director, New York Public Library
  - Lyman, Charles M., 1947-59 (Box 47, Folder 998)
    New Haven lawyer
  - Maass, Richard, 1954-55 (Box 48, Folder 999)
    See also: The Manuscript Society, Box 49, folder 1033.
  - Mabbott, Thomas O., 1954-65 (Box 48, Folder 1000)
    Hunter College
  - MacColl, Alan, 1962-63 (Box 48, Folder 1001)
    Oxford, Donne
  - MacDonald, Hugh, 1936-40 (Box 48, Folder 1002)
  - MacDuff, Ewen, 1965-66 (Box 48, Folder 1003)
    Denham
  - Mack, Maynard, 1909-, 1938-75 (Box 48, Folder 1004-1005)
    Yale English department, Pope, good friend
  - Mackenzie, Norman, 1959-67 (Box 48, Folder 1006)
  - Mackerness, E. D., 1950 (Box 48, Folder 1007)
  - MacLean, Kenneth, 1959 (Box 48, Folder 1008)
    John Chappell
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-, 1940 (Box 48, Folder 1009)
    Index Society
  - MacMillan, Dougald, 1940-53 (Box 48, Folder 1010)
    UNC (Chapel Hill)
  - Macmillan Co., 1939-72 (Box 48, Folder 1011)
  - Macnutt, Richard, 1965-68 (Box 48, Folder 1012)
  - Maddison, Raymond E., 1965 Jul 29 (Box 48, Folder 1013)
  - Maggs Bros., Ltd., 1938-58 (Box 48, Folder 1014-1018)
  - Maggs Bros., Ltd., 1958-71 (Box 49, Folder 1019-1021)
  - Magnus, Gerhard, 1938-41 (Box 49, Folder 1022)
    Research assistant, periodical index, 1938-41
  - Mahl, Mary, 1971 (Box 49, Folder 1023)
    Promotion evaluation, USC
  - Mahler MSS (Montgomery et al.), 1967-68 (Box 49, Folder 1024)
  - Malone, Cecil L'Estrange, 1949-68 (Box 49, Folder 1025)
  - Malone, Herbert, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 1026)
  - Malone, Kemp, 1955-56 (Box 49, Folder 1027)
    MLA paper on Whythorne
  - Malone Commemorative Plaque, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 1028)
    See also: London County Council, Box 47, folder 978.
  - Malone, New York (Wead Library), 1948-52 (Box 49, Folder 1029)
  - Mansbridge, F. Ronald, 1940-72 (Box 49, Folder 1030)
    Columbia University Press, Yale University Press
  - Manuel, George Thomas, 1953-75 (Box 49, Folder 1031)
  - Manuscript (Wrexham Foundation), 1961 (Box 49, Folder 1032)
  - The Manuscript Society, 1954-71 (Box 49, Folder 1033)
    See also: Maass, Richard, Box 48, folder 999.
  - Manwaring, Elizabeth Wheeler, ca. 1879-1949, 1936-42 (Box 49, Folder 1034-1035)
    Wellesley, 18th century
  - Marcham & Co., F. H., 1950-51 (Box 49, Folder 1036)
  - Marchand, Leslie A., 1935-64 (Box 49, Folder 1037)
    Rutgers, Byron
  - Marder, Louis, 1951-68 (Box 49, Folder 1038)
    The Shakespeare Newsletter
  - Margenau, Henry, 1958-69 (Box 49, Folder 1039)
    Yale Physics Department, friend
  - Mariani, John F., 1970 (Box 49, Folder 1040)
    Landor
  - Markham, Sarah, 1976 (Box 49, Folder 1041)
  - Marks, Carol L., 1964-66 (Box 49, Folder 1042)
    Cornell, Traherne
  - Marlow, Jessie Havill, 1952-56 (Box 50, Folder 1043)
    Old family friend from Ohio
  - Martz, Louis Lohr, 1913-, 1952-76 (Box 50, Folder 1044)
    Yale English Department, good friend
  - Mason, Cyril A. F., 1936-46 (Box 50, Folder 1045-1050)
    Periodical index, research assistant (London)
  - Mason, John F. A., 1967-76 (Box 50, Folder 1051)
    Christ Church, Oxford, Sidney
  - Masterman, Sir John Cecil, 1891-1977, 1968-76 (Box 50, Folder 1052)
    The Double Cross System
  - Mathews, Elkin Ltd., 1938-66 (Box 51, Folder 1053-1054)
  - Matthews, Howard B., 1953-68 (Box 51, Folder 1055)
    Vice-President, Wesleyan
  - Matthews, William, 1942-67 (Box 51, Folder 1056)
    UCLA, diaries
  - May, Georges, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 1057)
    4th International Enlightenment Congress
  - Mayfield, John S., 1960-61 (Box 51, Folder 1058)
    Curator of MSS and Rare Books, Syracuse University
  - Mayhew, George, 1960-66 (Box 51, Folder 1059)
    Caltech, Swift
  - McAdam, Edward L., Jr., 1936-63 (Box 51, Folder 1060)
    NYU, Johnsonian
  - McAleer, John J., 1961-63 (Box 51, Folder 1061)
    Boston College, Malone
  - McAree, James G., 1966 (Box 51, Folder 1062)
    Western Washington State College, Ozias Humphry diary
  - McCague, Wilma G., 1953-55 (Box 51, Folder 1063)
  - McCarthy, William H., Jr., 1940-52 (Box 51, Folder 1064)
  - McConaughy, James L., 1935-41 (Box 51, Folder 1065)
    President, Wesleyan University
  - McCrillis, John O. C., 1976 Mar 19 (Box 51, Folder 1066)
  - McGill University, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 1067)
    Honorary degree, 1973
  - McHenry, Lawrence C., Jr., 1965-67 (Box 51, Folder 1068)
    Johnson's and Malone's medical history
  - McHugh, Roger, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 1069)
    University College, Dublin, Swift
  - McIntosh, Angus, 1960-64 (Box 51, Folder 1070)
    University of Edinburgh, Middle English MSS
  - McKay, George L., 1942-56 (Box 51, Folder 1071)
    Secretary, BSA, Grolier Club
  - McKenna, Norman C., 1972-76 (Box 51, Folder 1072)
  - McKerrow, Ronald Brunlees, 1872-1940, 1935-37 (Box 51, Folder 1073)
    Honorary Secretary, The Biographical Society
  - McKillop, Alan D., 1941-55 (Box 51, Folder 1074)
    Rice Institute, James Thomson
  - McLean, Ruari, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 1075)
    Motif magazine
  - McLeish & Sons, 1938-49 (Box 51, Folder 1076)
  - McManaway, James G., 1938-75 (Box 52, Folder 1077-1079)
  - McNutt, Homer E., 1957-73 (Box 52, Folder 1080)
  - McVey, William Mozart, 1906-, 1932-75 (Box 52, Folder 1081-1082)
    High school friend, sculptor
  - Mead, James J., Jr., 1941-64 (Box 52, Folder 1083)
    Friend on Wall Street
  - Meek, Ronald L., 1963 (Box 52, Folder 1084)
    Glasgow, Adam Smith MSS
  - Meeker, Thomas G., 1953-61 (Box 52, Folder 1085)
    Lawyer friend
  - Meikle, Henry W., 1935-38 (Box 52, Folder 1086)
  - Mengel, Elias F., Jr., 1964-74 (Box 52, Folder 1087)
  - Merritt, A. Tillman, 1955-56 (Box 52, Folder 1088)
    Department of Music, Harvard University, American Musicological Society
  - Messeri, Girolamo and Anne Mia (Grigorcia), 1956-69 (Box 52, Folder 1089)
    Roman friends
  - Metropolitan Club, 1946-74 (Box 52, Folder 1090)
  - Metzdorf, Robert Frederic, 1912-197?, 1939-68 (Box 52, Folder 1091-1092)
    Bibliophile
  - Michelmore, G., & Co., 1951-54 (Box 53, Folder 1093)
  - Middendorf, John Harlan, 1922-, 1958-70 (Box 53, Folder 1094)
    Columbia, Johnsonian
  - Milgate, Wesley, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 1095)
  - Millar, C. A., 1951 (Box 53, Folder 1096)
  - Miller, Henry K., 1970-71 (Box 53, Folder 1097)
    Princeton, MLA paper
  - Miller, J. Wesley, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 1098)
    Luttrell
  - Miller, William H., 1938-39 (Box 53, Folder 1099)
    Derrick
  - Millett, Fred B., 1939-67 (Box 53, Folder 1100-1104)
  - Milne, George, 1970-72 (Box 53, Folder 1105)
    McAdam "Nedschrift"
  - Mineka, Francis, 1958-66 (Box 53, Folder 1106)
    Cornell, J. S. Mill edition